Guide to the Movement (Protest) Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Underground and Radical Newspapers, 1946-1979; Series I
  - Veterans Stars and Stripes for Peace, 1970 April (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Viet Report, 1968 April-May (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Volume 3:6-7.
  - Vietnam
    See: Indochina
  - Vietnam Summer News, 1967 August 25 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - View from the Bottom, 1969 August 7-21, September 18-December 25, undated, 1970 February 18-October 29 (Box 22, Folder 6-13)
    Volumes 1:2-1:3, 1:5-2:5.
  - Virginia Weekly, 1972 January (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Volume 4:2.
  - Vocations for Social Change
    See: Work Force
  - The Volunteer, 1973 April (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - La Voz de Colorado, 1976 November 15 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Voz Operária (Brazil), 1972 May (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Number 87.
  - War Bulletin, 1972 May 10, September 8-21 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Volumes 6, 17.
  - War Resisters League News, 1967 July-August (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Washington Free Press, 1972 November (Box 23, Folder 7)
    Volume 2:18.
  - Washington Peace Center Newsletter, 1971 October (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Wassaja, 1976 October-December (Box 23, Folder 9)
    Volumes 4:10, 4:11-12.
  - Weekly People, 1971 May 22 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    Volume 81:8.
  - West Side News, 1967 July 6 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    Volume 33:16.
  - Wild Raspberry, 1971 Aug, October (Box 23, Folder 12)
    Volumes 1:6-1:7.
  - Win, 1972 November 1 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    Volume 8:17.
  - Winter Soldier, 1973 November (Box 23, Folder 14)
    Volume 3:9.
  - Wisconsin Patriot, 1971 December-1974 Nov, 1975 January-December (Box 24, Folder 1-5)
    Volumes 1:1, 2:1-2:9, 3:1-3:11, 4:1-4:8, 5:1-5:6.
  - Women: A Journal of Liberation, 1970 Fall, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Volumes 2:1, 2:3.
  - Woodwind, 1971 October 13 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Workers League posters and fliers, Circa 1970 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Work Force, 1971 March-Aug, 1972 May-Aug, 1973 January-June (Box 24, Folder 9-10)
    Volumes 22-24, 29-30, 3 unnumbered issues.
  - Write On, 1973 September-October (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - X, Circa 1970 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    Volumes 8, 14.
  - YLO. Young Lords Organization, 1970 February-March (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Young Socialist, 1973 September (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Young Worker, 1976 May (Box 24, Folder 15)
- Pamphlets, Leaflets, and Broadsides, 1946-1979; Series II
  The series is arranged alphabetically by subject; some variations.
  - Africa, 1969-1972 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Anti-War: General, 1964-1971 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Australia, 1970-1972 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Bibliographies and Book Lists, Circa 1960s-1970s (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Birth Control, 1969-1972 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Black Panther Party, 1969-1971 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Canada, 1970-1971 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - China, 1946-1974 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Civil Rights
    - March on Washington
      - Memorabilia, 1963 August 28 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Twentieth anniversary, 1983 August (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Conservative Protest, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Counter-Culture, 1968-1976 (Box 26, Folder 2-3)
  - The Draft and the Military, 1968-1972 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    See also: Indochina
    - Netherlands, 1972-1975 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Drugs, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Eastern Europe, 1955-1973 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - East Germany, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 2-3)
  - Ecology, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - The Economy, Circa 1960-1970 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Education, 1966-1971 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Education, Alternative
    - Arkansas, 1973-1976 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - California, 1976-1977 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Colorado
      - Boulder, 1975-1977 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Denver
        - Denver Free University. Bulletin, course lists, 1973-1977 (Box 27, Folder 4)
        - Key Magazine, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 5)
        - Mother Jones' Journal, 1976-1977 (Box 27, Folder 6)
        - The Teacher Paper, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - District of Columbia (Washington), 1975-1976 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Kansas, 1975-1976 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Massachusetts
      - Amherst, Circa 1971 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Cambridge, 1972-1975 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Michigan, Circa 1972 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Minnesota, 1975-1977 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Missouri, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - New Jersey, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - New York, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Tennessee, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - France, 1967-1968 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Gay Liberation, 1964-1972 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Germany, 1968-1975 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Greece, 1971-1974 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Imperialism, Circa 1966-1969 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Indochina, 1965-1975 (Box 29, Folder 1-5)
  - Ireland, Circa 1970s (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Latin America
    - Brazil, 1960-1972 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
    - Chile, 1972-1973 (Box 30, Folder 3-4)
    - Cuba, Circa 1970 (Box 30, Folder 5-6)
    - General, 1963-1973 (Box 30, Folder 7-9)
    - Puerto Rico, Circa 1975 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Labor and the Working Class, 1960-1973 (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
  - March on Washington, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - May Day (Washington, DC), 1971 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Mexican Americans, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Middle East, 1966-1974 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Movement: General, 1964-1975 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Netherlands, 1973 April (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Pakistan and India, 1962-1971 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Peace Corps, Circa 1969 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - People's Bicentennial Commission, 1974-1976 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Politics and Theory, Circa 1967-1972 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Power Structure Research, 1965-1970 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Prison Reform, Circa 1970 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Racism and Black Power, 1956-1974 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Religion, 1971-1976 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Southeast Asia (except Indo-China), 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Universities
    - American, 1967-1975 (Box 34, Folder 1-4)
      - Berkeley People's Park, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Free University Network, Circa 1974 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - New University Conference (NUC), 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Free Speech Movement, 1964-1975 (Box 35)
    - German
      The literature is arranged chronologically according to the university at which it was distributed. Thus, literature published by a student group in Munich, but distributed in Bonn, is filed under Bonn. No attempt has been made to arrange the material by party.
      - Basel, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 1)
        Student leaflets and newspapers, some of which were issued on the occasion of the suicide of the German terrorists in Stammheim prison, October 1977.
      - Berlin
        - Student leaflets and newspapers
          - 1970-1975 (Box 38, Folder 1-10)
          - 1975-1976 (Box 39, Folder 1-6)
          - 1974-1976 (Box 44, Folder 1)
        - Notgemeinschaft für eine Freie Universität. Publications, 1973-1978 (Box 40, Folder 1-7)
      - Bonn, student leaflets and newspapers
        - 1973-1977 (Box 41, Folder 1-7)
        - 1977 (Box 44, Folder 2-3)
        - 1978 (Box 45, Folder 1-5)
        - 1978-1979 (Box 47, Folder 1-6)
      - Freiburg, 1977-1978 (Box 46, Folder 2-3)
      - Hamburg, student leaflets and newspapers
        - 1977-1978 (Box 46, Folder 4)
          Some issued on the occasion of the suicide of the German terrorists in Stammheim prison, October 1977.
        - 1978 (Box 39, Folder 7)
        - 1979 (Box 48, Folder 1-3)
      - Paris, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Reference materials
        - Bibliography. Revolutionäre Bücherei, 1976 (Box 42, Folder 1)
        - Domes, Jürgen and Armin Paul Frank. "The Tribulations of the Free University of Berlin.", Undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
          Reprinted from Minerva. v.13, no. 2. Summer 1975. p.[183]-199.
        - Leonhard, Wolfgang, "Kommunistische Strömungen und Organisationen in der Bundesrepublik Deutschland.", 1976 (Box 42, Folder 3)
          Published in Was ist Kommunismus. Wandlungen eine Idealogie. C. Bertelsman, 1976. 19 p. (typescript, electrostatic copy)
        - Lönnendonker, Siegward and Tilman Fichter. Freie Universität Berlin 1948-1973. Hochschule im Umbruch. (Box 42, Folder 4-6)
          Berlin, Freie Universität, 1973-1974. Teil I. 1945-1949 Gegengündung wozu? Teil II. 1941-1957 Konsolidierung um jeden Preis. Teil III. 1957-1964 Auf dem Weg in den Dissens (Dokumentation FU Berlin, nr.12/73. 13/73, 14/73)
        - Langguth, Gerd. Die Entwicklung der Protestbewegung in der Bundesrepublik 1968-1975. (Box 43, Folder 1-4)
          Thesis (Ph.D.) (Rheinischen Friedrich-Wilhelm Universität) 1975. 410 p. (typescript, electrostatic copy). Published as Die Protestbewegung in der Bundesrepublik Deutschland 1968-1976. Wissenschaft und Politik, 1976
    - Prague (headquarters). International Union of Students Posters, 1972-1977, undated (Box 36, Folder 1-5)
  - Vegetarianism, Circa 1971-1976 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Welfare, Undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Women's Liberation [U. S.], 1968-1976 (Box 37, Folder 3-7)
  - Women's Liberation [Germany]
    Assembled under this heading are pamphlets, issues of periodicals, and other materials collected during 1974 and 1975. Almost all the items are from Germany with a few from other German-speaking areas.
    - Periodicals (incomplete runs)
      - Alternative. Berlin., 1976 June-July (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Auf. Eine Frauenzeitschrift. Vienna, 1975 Jan, Jun, 1976 May (Box 49, Folder 2)
        Numbers 1 ,4, 7.
      - Clio. Berlin, 1976 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Courage. Berliner Frauenzeitung. Berlin, 1976 June, 1977 June-Jul, November-December (Box 49, Folder 4)
        Numbers 0, 6/7, 11-12.
      - Efa. Emanzipation, Frauen, Argumente. Löln-Niehl, 1974-1975 (Box 49, Folder 5)
        Numbers 5, 9.
      - Emma. Köln., 1977 Jul, October (Box 49, Folder 6)
        Numbers 7, 10.
      - Der Feminist. München., 1977 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Fempol-druck. Basel., 1975 May-July (Box 49, Folder 8)
        Numbers 1, 2.
      - Frauezitig. Zürich., 1975 July (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Heim und Erzieher. Berlin., 1976 August (Box 49, Folder 10)
        Number 8.
      - Lesbenfront. Zürich., 1977 June (Box 49, Folder 11)
        Number 4.
      - Lesbenpresse. West Berlin., 1975 Feb, Jun, 1977 May (Box 49, Folder 12)
        Numbers 1, 2, 5.
      - Lover. Leende, Netherlands, 1976 (Box 49, Folder 13)
      - Mamas Pfirsiche, Circa 1976 (Box 49, Folder 14)
      - Unsere Kleine Zeitung (UKZ). Berlin, 1975 March-November (Box 49, Folder 15)
        Numbers 2-4, 5/1, 6/1, 7/1, 8/1, 9/1.
      - Verlag Frauenoffensiv. Munich., 1976-1977 (Box 49, Folder 16)
        Catalogue of a feminist press and some literature on abortion and Paragraph 218.
    - Materials pertaining to women's liberation arranged alphabetically by city
      - Berlin
        - Frauenbuchvertreib
          - Frauenhefte, 1977 July (Box 50, Folder 1)
          - Partnerin, 1977 August-September (Box 50, Folder 1)
            Number 7:3.
        - Frauenxentrum, Circa 1976 (Box 50, Folder 2)
        - Homosexuelle Aktion West-Berlin (HAW), 1974 (Box 50, Folder 3-4)
      - Bonn. Frauentreffen., 1975 February 2 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Bremen. Frauenzeitung, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Darmstadt. Frauenzeitung., 1973 October (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Essener Frauenzentrum. Klara, 1977 May (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Frankfurt am Main. Congress, 1974 November (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - Freiburg
        - Frauengruppe Arbeitskreis, 1974 October (Box 50, Folder 10)
        - Aktionsgruppe: INFO, 1973 Oct, 1974 Jun, 1975 (Box 50, Folder 10)
          Numbers 2, 3, unnumbered.
        - Hamburg. Frauenzeitung., 1977 July (Box 50, Folder 11)
        - Hannover. Wir: Frauenzeitung., 1977 (Box 50, Folder 12)
        - Heidelberg. Frauenzentrum.
          - Frauen in der Plöck, Circa 1974 (Box 50, Folder 13)
          - Kleinstadt Lebenstreff, 1975 February 21-23 (Box 50, Folder 13)
        - Mannheim, Ludwigshafen. Nationaler Frauenkongress., 1975 February 7-9 (Box 50, Folder 14)
        - München. Frauenzeitung., 1974 Mar, September (Box 50, Folder 15)
          Numbers 3, 4.
        - Munich. Frauenzentrum., Circa 1975 (Box 50, Folder 16)
        - Stuttgart. Treffen, 1975 January 11-12 (Box 50, Folder 17)
        - Vienna. Aktion Unabhängiger Frauen, 1975 January 20 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Materials pertaining to abortion (Paragraph-218), Circa 1975-1976 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Literary publications pertaining to women's issues, 1976-1977 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Posters
    - Latin America, South America, Vietnam, Palestine and Poland, 1965-1977, undated (Box 51)
      Includes posters published by OSPAAAL, International Union of Students, OCLAE; includes posters commemorating World Day of Solidarity with Cuba.
    - Germany, 1970s, undated (Box 52)
      Includes posters published by SPD (German Workers), Nahost-Komitee Westberlin, Kommunistische Hochschulgruppe (KHG); also includes posters and periodicals, including Frauenbulletin, pertaining to women's liberation in Germany.
- Additional materials, 1952-1982; Accession 1984-M-004
  The newspapers are listed alphabetically by title. The collection of other printed material (pamphlets, broadsides, leaflets, etc.) is listed alphabetically by topic or geographical area.
  - Newspapers, 1977-1978
    - Arbeiterskampf, 1977 December 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Volume 7, number 120.
    - Die Neue Welt, 1977 May (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Number 3.
    - RCDS, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Rote Hilfe, 1977 December (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Number 10.
  - Printed material, 1952-1982
    - Africa, Circa 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Anti-war, 1958-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Communism, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Counter-culture, 1967-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Draft and the military, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Drugs, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Eastern Europe, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Ecology, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Education, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Food, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Germany, 1964-1980
      - General, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Berlin, 1975-1980
        - Agitation im Freizeitbereich: Proletarisches Lehrlingstheater "Rote Steine", 1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - Courage, 1979 September (Box 1, Folder 17)
        - Emma, 1979 Sep, 1980 August (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - Notgemeinschaft für eine freie Universität, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
      - Bonn. Deutsche Jungdemokraten: Vom Zivildienst zum Friedendienst, Circa 1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Frankfurt, 1972-1976
        - 88a in aktion, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Report über Bedrohungen der Demokratie, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Hamburg, 1978-1982
        - General, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        - Universities, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 4-7)
        - Universities, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Indo-china, 1953-1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Labor, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Latin America, 1961-1982 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
    - May Day 1971, Washington, D.C. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Mental health, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Middle East, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Movement, general, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - Nixon, 1962-1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Politics and theory, Circa 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Racism and black power, circa 1960-1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Religion, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Socialist youth, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Universities, 1968-1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Vegetarianism, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Women, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Abortion, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Women's liberation, 1969-1976 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Additional material, 1974-1982; Accession 1986-M-107
  Accession consists of pamphlets, which are arranged alphabetically.
  - Bahro, Rudolf. Rudolf Bahro Interviews Himself, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Benn, Tony. The Levellers and the English Democratic Tradition, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Benn, Tony. Why America Needs Democratic Socialism, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Boumediene, Houari. The Battle Against Underdevelopment, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Case of Rudolf Bahro: A Socialist in an East German Prison, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chomsky, Noam. East Timor and the Western Demcracies, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Coates, Ken. Socialists and the Labour Party, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cohen, Barry. The Black and White Minstrel Show: Carter, Young and Africa, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Deutscher, Tamara, Zuzana Bluh-Sling, and Ken Coates. The Struggle for Socialist Democracy...: Political Prisoners in Czechoslovakia and the USSR, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Eaton, John. Towards Socialism, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Eaton, John, Michael Barratt Brown, and Ken Coates. Economic Strategy for the Labour Movement: An Alternative, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwards, Dudley. The Last Stand of the Levellers, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwards, Dudley. The Soldiers' Revolt, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ENDpapers special, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Field, Frank and Steve Winyard. Low Wages Council, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "For Official Use Only": The Secret Plans of the West German Interior Ministry to Destroy the Russell Tribunal on Human Rights, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Found Guilty: The Verdict of the Russell Tribunal Session in Brussels, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hughes, John. Profit Trends and Price Controls, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Jenkins, Peter. Where Trotskyism Got Lost: The Restoration of European Democracy after the Second World War, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mandel, Ernest. Why They Invaded Czechoslovakia, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Markovic, Mihailo. On the Legal Institutions of Socialist Democracy, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Medvedev, Roy A. How I Ran for Election and How I Lost, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Porter, Robin. Child Labour in Hong Kong, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Third Russell Tribunal: Berufsverbote Condemned, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Torture in Brazil: Testimony Given to the Rome Session of the Russell Tribunal, Circa 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Warren, Bill and Mike Prior. Advanced Capitalism and Backward Socialism, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional materials, 1949-80; Accession 2001-M-051
  Donated by David Dellinger, the addition mainly consists of publications for which he played a central role, including Liberation, Seven Days, Individual Action and Cooperative Living.
  The publications are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - The Black Panther, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 90-91)
  - Brother: A Male Liberation Newsletter, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Cooperative Living, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Good Times, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Liberation
    - 1956 March-1962 December (Box 1, Folder 2-19)
    - 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 20-33)
    - 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 34-44)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 45-51)
    - 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 52-60)
    - 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 61-68)
  - Quash, 1975 December (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Resistance, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Seven Days
    - 1975 March-1977 April (Box 6, Folder 71-77)
    - 1977 May-1980 April (Box 7, Folder 78-88)
    - Promotional, business, and editorial material (Box 7, Folder 89)